<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab on gavinmassey.net</title>
    <link>https://gavinmassey.net/categories/lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lab on gavinmassey.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gavinmassey.net/categories/lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lab 1: vSphere 7 on VMware Workstation Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/lab1-vsphere-7-on-vmware-workstation-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/lab1-vsphere-7-on-vmware-workstation-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to this tutorial on establishing a VMware vSphere 7 and vCenter Server Appliance (VCMA) 7 lab on a Windows 11 system. Our aim is to create a functional virtual lab environment using VMware Player 17, focusing primarily on VMware&amp;rsquo;s virtualization technologies. We will set up two ESXi 7 hosts, providing a hands-on experience with VMware&amp;rsquo;s advanced virtualization platform in a nested virtualization context.&#xA;In this lab, we will configure the following key components:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 2: Creating an ESXi Cluster and Integrating with vCenter</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/lab2-creating-esxi-cluster-with-vcenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/lab2-creating-esxi-cluster-with-vcenter/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and Purpose In a virtualized environment, clustering is a powerful technique that dramatically enhances resource management, availability, and scalability. An ESXi cluster, managed by vCenter, is a collection of ESXi hosts aggregated to provide a robust, shared infrastructure for virtual machines. This setup allows for:&#xA;High Availability (HA): In case of a host failure, HA automatically restarts the VMs on other hosts within the cluster, minimizing downtime and ensuring continuous availability of services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WIM and CIM Lab Exercises</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/cim-lab-exercises/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/cim-lab-exercises/</guid>
      <description>Lab Exercise 1: System Overview Objective: Get an overview of your computer system&amp;rsquo;s properties.&#xA;Task: Retrieve information about the operating system, including its version, last boot up time, and the number of users currently logged on.&#xA;Command Hint: Get-CimInstance -ClassName CIM_OperatingSystem Task: Fetch the computer&amp;rsquo;s name, manufacturer, model, and the total physical memory.&#xA;Command Hint: Get-CimInstance -ClassName Win32_ComputerSystem Lab Exercise 2: Disk Analysis Objective: Analyze the disk space usage and health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple VMware Windows Infrastructure Lab</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/simple-vmware-windows-infrastructure-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/simple-vmware-windows-infrastructure-lab/</guid>
      <description>Objective This guide provides step-by-step instructions to set up a virtual environment using PowerShell. It includes configuring one Virtual Machine as a Domain Controller (DC), another as an Application Server (APP server), and a Windows 10 Client.&#xA;1. Configure Server2022 as DC To set up the Domain Controller, execute the following commands in PowerShell:&#xA;# Configuring IP address for &amp;#39;Ethernet&amp;#39; interface New-NetIPAddress -IPAddress 10.0.0.2 -InterfaceAlias &amp;#34;Ethernet0&amp;#34; -PrefixLength 24 -DefaultGateway 10.0.0.1 # Set DNS client server address post AD DS installation Set-DnsClientServerAddress -InterfaceAlias &amp;#34;Ethernet0&amp;#34; -ServerAddresses 127.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
