<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on gavinmassey.net</title>
    <link>https://gavinmassey.net/categories/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on gavinmassey.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gavinmassey.net/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Guide to Storage in Datacenters and VMware</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/comprehensive-guide-to-storage-in-datacenters-and-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/comprehensive-guide-to-storage-in-datacenters-and-vmware/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the dynamic and ever-evolving field of data center technologies and VMware storage solutions, understanding the foundational concepts and terminologies is crucial for anyone embarking on a journey in this domain. This article serves as a starting point, aiming to demystify the complex landscape of storage technologies and their integration in virtualized environments, particularly focusing on VMware.&#xA;SCSI and iSCSI Topics SCSI Fundamentals SCSI, standing for Small Computer System Interface, is a set of standards for physically connecting and transferring data between computers and peripheral devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netstat Quick Reference</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/netstat-quick-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/netstat-quick-reference/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Netstat, a command-line tool available in Windows Server, is a powerful utility for network diagnostics and statistics. It provides detailed information about network connections, routing tables, interface statistics, and more. This tool is essential for network administrators and IT professionals to monitor, diagnose, and troubleshoot network-related issues on a Windows Server. Below is a list of common usages of Netstat on Windows Server.&#xA;List of Netstat Usages on Windows Server Display All Active Connections:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nslookup Quick Reference Guide</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/nslookup-quick-reference-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/nslookup-quick-reference-guide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction nslookup is a network administration command-line tool available in most operating systems, including Windows, macOS, and Linux. It is used for querying the Domain Name System (DNS) to obtain domain name or IP address mapping information. This tool is essential for network diagnostics and troubleshooting DNS issues.&#xA;Key Features of nslookup Query DNS Records: nslookup can query specific DNS record types, such as A (address), MX (mail exchange), NS (name server), and TXT (text) records.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the &#39;net&#39; command in Windows</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/using-the-net-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/using-the-net-command/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The net command in Windows is a versatile utility used for a wide array of network and system management tasks. This command-line tool can manage user accounts, network resources, services, and more, making it an essential tool for administrators. This guide delves into the use of the net command with detailed examples and background information on each functionality.&#xA;Managing User Accounts and Groups Create a New User:&#xA;net user Emily StrongP@ssword123 /add This command creates a new user named Emily with a specified password.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Port Security</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/cisco-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/cisco-port-security/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cisco Port Security is a feature on Cisco switches that enhances the security of the network by controlling access to switch ports. It limits the devices that can connect to a switch port, thus preventing unauthorized network access.&#xA;Use Cases for Cisco Port Security Preventing Unauthorized Network Access: Restricts access to a network by allowing only known MAC addresses to connect. Protecting Against MAC Address Spoofing: Prevents potential attackers from impersonating other devices on the network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Implementing Private VLANs in Cisco Networks</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-and-implementing-private-vlans.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-and-implementing-private-vlans.md/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Private VLANs (PVLANs) are an advanced feature in VLAN technology, offering enhanced network segmentation and security. They are particularly useful in environments where there is a need for isolation between devices within the same VLAN. This article explores the use cases, theoretical background, and practical implementation of Private VLANs, with a focus on Cisco switch configurations.&#xA;Use Cases for Private VLANs Private VLANs are ideal in scenarios where you need to restrict communication between devices on the same traditional VLAN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP)</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-cisco-discovery-protocol-cdp.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-cisco-discovery-protocol-cdp.md/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP) is a network layer protocol used in Cisco devices to share information about directly connected devices. As a proprietary protocol of Cisco, CDP plays a crucial role in network management and troubleshooting by allowing network devices to discover and learn about each other.&#xA;Use Cases for CDP CDP is particularly useful in:&#xA;Network Mapping: Automatically discovering Cisco devices within the network, helping in creating a network topology map.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) in Network Engineering</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-spanning-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-spanning-tree/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) is a network protocol that ensures a loop-free topology for any bridged Ethernet local area network. The fundamental purpose of STP is to prevent network disruptions caused by loops, which are common in redundant network topologies.&#xA;Use Cases for STP STP is critical in networks where redundancy is essential for reliability. Key applications include:&#xA;Preventing Network Loops: Automatically identifies and disables redundant paths in a network, preventing loops that can cause broadcast storms and network failures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) in Cisco Networks</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vtp-in-cisco-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vtp-in-cisco-networks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) is a Cisco-proprietary protocol that simplifies the management of VLAN configurations across a network. It is particularly useful in large networks with numerous switches, helping to manage VLANs more efficiently and ensuring consistent configurations.&#xA;Use Cases for VTP Simplifying VLAN management across multiple switches. Ensuring consistent VLAN configuration and avoiding mismatches. Reducing administrative tasks related to VLAN maintenance. Theory of VTP VTP operates within a designated domain, with switches set to different modes:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VLANs</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vlans/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Virtual Local Area Networks (VLANs) are a fundamental concept in modern network design, offering a powerful tool for network administrators to segment and manage network traffic effectively. At its core, a VLAN is a logical subdivision of a network, distinguished from a traditional LAN by its ability to separate devices regardless of their physical location. This separation is crucial for several reasons, primarily enhancing network efficiency, security, and scalability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up pfSense on VMware Workstation Pro</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-pfsense-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-pfsense-router/</guid>
      <description>In a virtual lab environment, often you will need a network device to accurately reflect a real-world environment. pfSense is a good option and is easy to use.&#xA;1. Download pfSense Image Visit pfSense Download Page: Go to the pfSense download page. Select Version and Architecture: Choose the latest stable release and select the architecture that matches your system (most likely AMD64). Select Installer Type: Choose the installer type. For VMware, the CD Image (ISO) installer is typically used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up VyOS on VMware Workstation Pro</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-vyos-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-vyos-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>1. Download VyOS ISO Visit VyOS Download Page: Go to VyOS download page. Select Version: Choose the latest stable release or a version that suits your needs. Download ISO: Click on the download link for the ISO image and save it to your computer. 2. Create a New Virtual Machine in VMware Open VMware Workstation Pro: Launch the VMware Workstation Pro application. Create New Virtual Machine: Select &amp;ldquo;Create a New Virtual Machine&amp;rdquo; or use &amp;ldquo;File&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;New Virtual Machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Virtual Networking Under the Hood</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-virtual-networking-behind-the-scenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-virtual-networking-behind-the-scenes/</guid>
      <description>VMware Workstation performs a significant amount of low-level networking operations to manage virtual networks for virtual machines (VMs). To achieve this, it installs special drivers and creates virtual network devices that integrate with the host system&amp;rsquo;s networking stack. Here&amp;rsquo;s how VMware modifies your system to enable its networking capabilities:&#xA;Virtual Network Adapters: VMware installs virtual network adapters for different types of networks (like VMnet1 for Host-Only and VMnet8 for NAT by default).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Workstation Pro Networking FAQ</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-virtual-networking-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-virtual-networking-faq/</guid>
      <description>Contents What does &amp;ldquo;Connect a Host Virtual Adapter to This Network&amp;rdquo; Mean? What IP Address Will the Host Virtual Adapter Receive? Why Does the Host Adapter Get an IP Outside the DHCP Range? Does a NAT Network Require a Host Virtual Adapter to Function? How Does VMware Handle NAT Without a Host Network Adapter? Does VMware Install Special Networking Drivers or Change the Network Stack? What does &amp;ldquo;Connect a Host Virtual Adapter to This Network&amp;rdquo; Mean?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VMware Virtual Network Types and IP Addressing</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/about-vmware-workstation-virtual-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/about-vmware-workstation-virtual-networks/</guid>
      <description>When working with VMware Workstation Pro, setting up your network correctly is crucial for ensuring that your virtual machines (VMs) communicate properly with the host machine and among themselves. VMware provides various types of virtual networks, each serving different needs. This article will cover the three main types: Bridged, NAT, and Host-Only networking.&#xA;Bridged Networking Overview Bridged networking connects a VM directly to the host machine&amp;rsquo;s network, using the host&amp;rsquo;s physical network adapter.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
