<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Switching on gavinmassey.net</title>
    <link>https://gavinmassey.net/categories/switching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Switching on gavinmassey.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gavinmassey.net/categories/switching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Port Security</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/cisco-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/cisco-port-security/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cisco Port Security is a feature on Cisco switches that enhances the security of the network by controlling access to switch ports. It limits the devices that can connect to a switch port, thus preventing unauthorized network access.&#xA;Use Cases for Cisco Port Security Preventing Unauthorized Network Access: Restricts access to a network by allowing only known MAC addresses to connect. Protecting Against MAC Address Spoofing: Prevents potential attackers from impersonating other devices on the network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Implementing Private VLANs in Cisco Networks</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-and-implementing-private-vlans.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-and-implementing-private-vlans.md/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Private VLANs (PVLANs) are an advanced feature in VLAN technology, offering enhanced network segmentation and security. They are particularly useful in environments where there is a need for isolation between devices within the same VLAN. This article explores the use cases, theoretical background, and practical implementation of Private VLANs, with a focus on Cisco switch configurations.&#xA;Use Cases for Private VLANs Private VLANs are ideal in scenarios where you need to restrict communication between devices on the same traditional VLAN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP)</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-cisco-discovery-protocol-cdp.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-cisco-discovery-protocol-cdp.md/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP) is a network layer protocol used in Cisco devices to share information about directly connected devices. As a proprietary protocol of Cisco, CDP plays a crucial role in network management and troubleshooting by allowing network devices to discover and learn about each other.&#xA;Use Cases for CDP CDP is particularly useful in:&#xA;Network Mapping: Automatically discovering Cisco devices within the network, helping in creating a network topology map.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) in Network Engineering</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-spanning-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-spanning-tree/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) is a network protocol that ensures a loop-free topology for any bridged Ethernet local area network. The fundamental purpose of STP is to prevent network disruptions caused by loops, which are common in redundant network topologies.&#xA;Use Cases for STP STP is critical in networks where redundancy is essential for reliability. Key applications include:&#xA;Preventing Network Loops: Automatically identifies and disables redundant paths in a network, preventing loops that can cause broadcast storms and network failures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) in Cisco Networks</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vtp-in-cisco-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vtp-in-cisco-networks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) is a Cisco-proprietary protocol that simplifies the management of VLAN configurations across a network. It is particularly useful in large networks with numerous switches, helping to manage VLANs more efficiently and ensuring consistent configurations.&#xA;Use Cases for VTP Simplifying VLAN management across multiple switches. Ensuring consistent VLAN configuration and avoiding mismatches. Reducing administrative tasks related to VLAN maintenance. Theory of VTP VTP operates within a designated domain, with switches set to different modes:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VLANs</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vlans/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Virtual Local Area Networks (VLANs) are a fundamental concept in modern network design, offering a powerful tool for network administrators to segment and manage network traffic effectively. At its core, a VLAN is a logical subdivision of a network, distinguished from a traditional LAN by its ability to separate devices regardless of their physical location. This separation is crucial for several reasons, primarily enhancing network efficiency, security, and scalability.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
