<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on gavinmassey.net</title>
    <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on gavinmassey.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gavinmassey.net/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing PowerShell Efficiency With A Customized Profile</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/asd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/asd/</guid>
      <description>Introduction PowerShell is an indispensable tool for Windows system administrators and power users. Customizing your PowerShell profile can significantly enhance your command-line experience, making it more efficient and user-friendly. This article provides a tailored PowerShell profile script with explanations for each customization, and guides you through setting up this profile on your system.&#xA;Custom PowerShell Profile Script with Explanations Here&amp;rsquo;s a PowerShell profile script, complete with comments explaining the functionality of each part:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Access Commands for Efficient Windows Administration</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/qucik-access-commands-for-windows-administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/qucik-access-commands-for-windows-administration/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Streamline your system administration tasks with these quick-launch commands. Utilizing the Win + R shortcut, you can instantly access essential Windows tools, bypassing complex menus and saving valuable time. This guide offers a comprehensive list of commands for fast and efficient system management, perfect for any administrator or power user seeking to enhance productivity.&#xA;Command List Command Description appwiz.cpl Opens &amp;lsquo;Programs and Features&amp;rsquo; for uninstalling or changing programs. ncpa.cpl Opens &amp;lsquo;Network Connections&amp;rsquo; to manage network adapters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Guide to Storage in Datacenters and VMware</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/comprehensive-guide-to-storage-in-datacenters-and-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/comprehensive-guide-to-storage-in-datacenters-and-vmware/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the dynamic and ever-evolving field of data center technologies and VMware storage solutions, understanding the foundational concepts and terminologies is crucial for anyone embarking on a journey in this domain. This article serves as a starting point, aiming to demystify the complex landscape of storage technologies and their integration in virtualized environments, particularly focusing on VMware.&#xA;SCSI and iSCSI Topics SCSI Fundamentals SCSI, standing for Small Computer System Interface, is a set of standards for physically connecting and transferring data between computers and peripheral devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netstat Quick Reference</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/netstat-quick-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/netstat-quick-reference/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Netstat, a command-line tool available in Windows Server, is a powerful utility for network diagnostics and statistics. It provides detailed information about network connections, routing tables, interface statistics, and more. This tool is essential for network administrators and IT professionals to monitor, diagnose, and troubleshoot network-related issues on a Windows Server. Below is a list of common usages of Netstat on Windows Server.&#xA;List of Netstat Usages on Windows Server Display All Active Connections:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nslookup Quick Reference Guide</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/nslookup-quick-reference-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/nslookup-quick-reference-guide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction nslookup is a network administration command-line tool available in most operating systems, including Windows, macOS, and Linux. It is used for querying the Domain Name System (DNS) to obtain domain name or IP address mapping information. This tool is essential for network diagnostics and troubleshooting DNS issues.&#xA;Key Features of nslookup Query DNS Records: nslookup can query specific DNS record types, such as A (address), MX (mail exchange), NS (name server), and TXT (text) records.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the &#39;net&#39; command in Windows</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/using-the-net-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/using-the-net-command/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The net command in Windows is a versatile utility used for a wide array of network and system management tasks. This command-line tool can manage user accounts, network resources, services, and more, making it an essential tool for administrators. This guide delves into the use of the net command with detailed examples and background information on each functionality.&#xA;Managing User Accounts and Groups Create a New User:&#xA;net user Emily StrongP@ssword123 /add This command creates a new user named Emily with a specified password.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Port Security</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/cisco-port-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/cisco-port-security/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cisco Port Security is a feature on Cisco switches that enhances the security of the network by controlling access to switch ports. It limits the devices that can connect to a switch port, thus preventing unauthorized network access.&#xA;Use Cases for Cisco Port Security Preventing Unauthorized Network Access: Restricts access to a network by allowing only known MAC addresses to connect. Protecting Against MAC Address Spoofing: Prevents potential attackers from impersonating other devices on the network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Implementing Private VLANs in Cisco Networks</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-and-implementing-private-vlans.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-and-implementing-private-vlans.md/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Private VLANs (PVLANs) are an advanced feature in VLAN technology, offering enhanced network segmentation and security. They are particularly useful in environments where there is a need for isolation between devices within the same VLAN. This article explores the use cases, theoretical background, and practical implementation of Private VLANs, with a focus on Cisco switch configurations.&#xA;Use Cases for Private VLANs Private VLANs are ideal in scenarios where you need to restrict communication between devices on the same traditional VLAN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP)</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-cisco-discovery-protocol-cdp.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-cisco-discovery-protocol-cdp.md/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP) is a network layer protocol used in Cisco devices to share information about directly connected devices. As a proprietary protocol of Cisco, CDP plays a crucial role in network management and troubleshooting by allowing network devices to discover and learn about each other.&#xA;Use Cases for CDP CDP is particularly useful in:&#xA;Network Mapping: Automatically discovering Cisco devices within the network, helping in creating a network topology map.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) in Network Engineering</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-spanning-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-spanning-tree/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) is a network protocol that ensures a loop-free topology for any bridged Ethernet local area network. The fundamental purpose of STP is to prevent network disruptions caused by loops, which are common in redundant network topologies.&#xA;Use Cases for STP STP is critical in networks where redundancy is essential for reliability. Key applications include:&#xA;Preventing Network Loops: Automatically identifies and disables redundant paths in a network, preventing loops that can cause broadcast storms and network failures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) in Cisco Networks</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vtp-in-cisco-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vtp-in-cisco-networks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) is a Cisco-proprietary protocol that simplifies the management of VLAN configurations across a network. It is particularly useful in large networks with numerous switches, helping to manage VLANs more efficiently and ensuring consistent configurations.&#xA;Use Cases for VTP Simplifying VLAN management across multiple switches. Ensuring consistent VLAN configuration and avoiding mismatches. Reducing administrative tasks related to VLAN maintenance. Theory of VTP VTP operates within a designated domain, with switches set to different modes:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VLANs</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/understanding-vlans/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Virtual Local Area Networks (VLANs) are a fundamental concept in modern network design, offering a powerful tool for network administrators to segment and manage network traffic effectively. At its core, a VLAN is a logical subdivision of a network, distinguished from a traditional LAN by its ability to separate devices regardless of their physical location. This separation is crucial for several reasons, primarily enhancing network efficiency, security, and scalability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VTCA-DCV Certification Study Guide</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/vcta-dcv-2024-certification-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/vcta-dcv-2024-certification-exam/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to the Study Guide Welcome to this streamlined version of the study guide for the VMware Certified Technical Associate (VCTA) Exam 1V0-21.20. This guide is based on the comprehensive work of Valerio Passeri in his unofficial study guide. Leveraging the capabilities of generative AI, I have succinctly summarized each key section to provide a focused and efficient review. Please note that while I have strived for accuracy, this material does not carry any official endorsement or guarantee of accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 1: vSphere 7 on VMware Workstation Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/lab1-vsphere-7-on-vmware-workstation-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/lab1-vsphere-7-on-vmware-workstation-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to this tutorial on establishing a VMware vSphere 7 and vCenter Server Appliance (VCMA) 7 lab on a Windows 11 system. Our aim is to create a functional virtual lab environment using VMware Player 17, focusing primarily on VMware&amp;rsquo;s virtualization technologies. We will set up two ESXi 7 hosts, providing a hands-on experience with VMware&amp;rsquo;s advanced virtualization platform in a nested virtualization context.&#xA;In this lab, we will configure the following key components:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 2: Creating an ESXi Cluster and Integrating with vCenter</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/lab2-creating-esxi-cluster-with-vcenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2024/lab2-creating-esxi-cluster-with-vcenter/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and Purpose In a virtualized environment, clustering is a powerful technique that dramatically enhances resource management, availability, and scalability. An ESXi cluster, managed by vCenter, is a collection of ESXi hosts aggregated to provide a robust, shared infrastructure for virtual machines. This setup allows for:&#xA;High Availability (HA): In case of a host failure, HA automatically restarts the VMs on other hosts within the cluster, minimizing downtime and ensuring continuous availability of services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware A Brief Guide to the VMware Ecosystem: Understanding Key Products and Technologies</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>vSphere VMware vSphere stands as a pivotal solution in data center management, offering advanced virtualization capabilities with a focus on scalability, performance, and efficiency. vSphere achieves this by abstracting and pooling the underlying hardware resources of physical servers, allowing for the creation and management of multiple virtual machines (VMs) on a single physical host.&#xA;Central to vSphere&amp;rsquo;s functionality is the ESXi hypervisor, which directly interacts with the hardware and is responsible for allocating resources to VMs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide, Part 1 - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-1-study-guide-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-1-study-guide-intro/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CLF-C02) Study Guide series! If you&amp;rsquo;re preparing for the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner exam, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place. This comprehensive series is designed to help you systematically cover all the essential topics from the official AWS Cloud Practitioner exam guide.&#xA;About This Study Guide In this series, I&amp;rsquo;ve broken down the AWS CLF-C02 exam guide into six parts, each focusing on a specific domain or topic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide, Part 2 - &#34;Knowledge of&#34; Sections</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-2-knowledge-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-2-knowledge-of/</guid>
      <description>Article Series Index Part 1 - Introduction Part 2 - &amp;ldquo;Knowledge of&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 3 - &amp;ldquo;Skill in&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 4 - Technologies and Concepts Part 5 - In Scope Services Part 6 - Summary The following compilation includes content exclusively from the &amp;lsquo;Knowledge of&amp;rsquo; sections of the AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide. These sections have been systematically divided and organized into separate articles for your convenience. For comprehensive information, please refer to the corresponding sections in the other parts of this guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide, Part 3 - &#34;Skill in&#34; Sections</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-3-skills-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-3-skills-in/</guid>
      <description>Article Series Index Part 1 - Introduction Part 2 - &amp;ldquo;Knowledge of&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 3 - &amp;ldquo;Skill in&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 4 - Technologies and Concepts Part 5 - In Scope Services Part 6 - Summary The following compilation includes content exclusively from the &amp;lsquo;Skills in&amp;rsquo; sections of the AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide. These sections have been systematically divided and organized into separate articles for your convenience. For comprehensive information, please refer to the corresponding sections in the other parts of this guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide, Part 4 - Technologies and Concepts</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-4-technologies-and-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-4-technologies-and-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Article Series Index Part 1 - Introduction Part 2 - &amp;ldquo;Knowledge of&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 3 - &amp;ldquo;Skill in&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 4 - Technologies and Concepts Part 5 - In Scope Services Part 6 - Summary The following compilation includes content exclusively from the &amp;lsquo;Technologies and Concepts&amp;rsquo; section of the AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide. These sections have been systematically divided and organized into separate articles for your convenience. For comprehensive information, please refer to the corresponding sections in the other parts of this guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide, Part 5 - In Scope Services</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-5-in-scope-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-5-in-scope-services/</guid>
      <description>Article Series Index Part 1 - Introduction Part 2 - &amp;ldquo;Knowledge of&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 3 - &amp;ldquo;Skill in&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 4 - Technologies and Concepts Part 5 - In Scope Services Part 6 - Summary The following compilation includes content exclusively from the &amp;lsquo;In Scope Services&amp;rsquo; section of the AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide. These sections have been systematically divided and organized into separate articles for your convenience. For comprehensive information, please refer to the corresponding sections in the other parts of this guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Cloud Practitioners Exam Guide, Part 6 - Summary</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-6-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-clf-c02/aws-clf-c02-part-6-summary/</guid>
      <description>Article Series Index Part 1 - Introduction Part 2 - &amp;ldquo;Knowledge of&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 3 - &amp;ldquo;Skill in&amp;rdquo; Sections Part 4 - Technologies and Concepts Part 5 - In Scope Services Part 6 - Summary Cloud Concepts Cost-effective and scalable with a pay-as-you-go pricing model. Global infrastructure offering high availability and speed of deployment. Focus on high availability, elasticity, and agility. Operational excellence, security, reliability, performance efficiency, cost optimization, and sustainability are pillars of the AWS Well-Architected Framework.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory Domain Services (ADDS) Management</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/adds-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/adds-management/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Active Directory Domain Services (ADDS) is a foundational aspect of managing Windows-based networks, offering robust tools for managing users, computers, and other resources within an organization. This comprehensive guide delves into various key aspects of ADDS management, providing insights and practical instructions on how to efficiently use command line tools, PowerShell, and the Best Practices Analyzer (BPA) to maintain and optimize your Active Directory environment.&#xA;Firstly, we explore how to check for replication errors in your Active Directory environment, using both command line tools like dcdiag and repadmin, and PowerShell commands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying PowerShell&#39;s Parameter Binding: How Objects Match Up to Cmdlet Parameters</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/parameter-binding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/parameter-binding/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell&amp;rsquo;s true power lies in its object-oriented nature and the ability to pipe objects from one cmdlet to another. Understanding how PowerShell matches piped object data to cmdlet parameters is crucial for writing efficient and effective scripts. This article delves into the algorithm behind this matching process and how you can anticipate it using the Get-Help documentation.&#xA;Understanding Parameter Binding in PowerShell When you pipe data from one cmdlet to another in PowerShell, the system uses a process called parameter binding to match the piped object data to the parameters of the receiving cmdlet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain Controller vs Global Catalog in Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/global-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/global-catalog/</guid>
      <description>In Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Active Directory (AD), Domain Controllers (DCs) and Global Catalogs (GCs) are crucial components, each with distinct roles and functions.&#xA;Domain Controller (DC) Primary Role: Handles authentication, authorization, and directory services within its domain. Data Scope: Manages the full Active Directory database for its domain, containing detailed information for each object. Functionality: Responds to security authentication requests, manages user and computer accounts, and enforces security policies. Replication: Every DC can update the directory and replicate changes to other DCs, ensuring network-wide consistency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Terraform</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/getting-started-with-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/getting-started-with-terraform/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Terraform is an open-source infrastructure as code software tool that enables you to safely and predictably create, change, and improve infrastructure. It codifies cloud APIs into declarative configuration files. This article will guide you through launching an Amazon EC2 instance and configuring its security group using Terraform.&#xA;Pre-requisites Before starting, ensure you have the following:&#xA;Set up AWS Environment: Have an AWS account with necessary permissions. Install Terraform: Download and install the Terraform CLI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPO Management</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/group-policy-object-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/group-policy-object-management/</guid>
      <description>Group Policy Objects (GPOs) are a pivotal component in Windows environments for efficient system administration and security management. This comprehensive guide dives into the nuances of GPO management, addressing common questions and providing practical exercises to enhance your understanding and skills.&#xA;From the basics of Active Directory (AD) structure to advanced topics like GPO inheritance and loopback processing, we cover a wide array of subjects critical for IT professionals. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to refine your existing knowledge or starting from scratch, this article offers valuable insights into optimizing your Windows network using GPOs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Monitoring AD DS Sites and Replication using PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/guide-to-monitoring-ad-ds-sites-and-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/guide-to-monitoring-ad-ds-sites-and-replication/</guid>
      <description>Overview This guide provides PowerShell commands for effective monitoring of Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) Sites and Replication, ensuring operational health and efficiency.&#xA;Preparing the Environment Initial Setup: Begin on a generic server, for example, Server01. Open Windows PowerShell to execute the following commands. Commands for Monitoring Replication Recalculate Inbound Replication Topology:&#xA;Repadmin /kcc Recalculates the inbound replication topology for Server01. Display Replication Status:&#xA;Repadmin /showrepl Shows the replication status for each domain controller.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up pfSense on VMware Workstation Pro</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-pfsense-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-pfsense-router/</guid>
      <description>In a virtual lab environment, often you will need a network device to accurately reflect a real-world environment. pfSense is a good option and is easy to use.&#xA;1. Download pfSense Image Visit pfSense Download Page: Go to the pfSense download page. Select Version and Architecture: Choose the latest stable release and select the architecture that matches your system (most likely AMD64). Select Installer Type: Choose the installer type. For VMware, the CD Image (ISO) installer is typically used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up VyOS on VMware Workstation Pro</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-vyos-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-vyos-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>1. Download VyOS ISO Visit VyOS Download Page: Go to VyOS download page. Select Version: Choose the latest stable release or a version that suits your needs. Download ISO: Click on the download link for the ISO image and save it to your computer. 2. Create a New Virtual Machine in VMware Open VMware Workstation Pro: Launch the VMware Workstation Pro application. Create New Virtual Machine: Select &amp;ldquo;Create a New Virtual Machine&amp;rdquo; or use &amp;ldquo;File&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;New Virtual Machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Trusts in Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/introduction-to-trusts-in-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/introduction-to-trusts-in-ad/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of network security and management, Trusts within Active Directory (AD) are pivotal. They are the backbone of domain interactions, enabling users in one domain to access resources in another. This guide delves into the intricacies of these trusts, outlining their types, implementations, and best practices for secure and efficient network management.&#xA;Types of Trusts in Active Directory Active Directory trusts can be broadly categorized into several types, each serving a unique purpose in the network infrastructure:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Domain Controllers With PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/managing-domain-controllers-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/managing-domain-controllers-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Important considerations Before making any changes to ADDS, make sure dependent network services such as DNS and DHCP will not be affected. Alway create a backup before making any changes. How do you verify which domain controller has the FSMO roles # Verifying FSMO Roles Assignment # Import Active Directory module # This module is necessary to run Active Directory-related cmdlets Import-Module ActiveDirectory # Retrieve domain information # This command gets information about the current domain $domain = Get-ADDomain # Retrieve forest information # This command gets information about the forest $forest = Get-ADForest # Display FSMO roles for the domain # PDCEmulator, RIDMaster, and InfrastructureMaster roles are domain-specific Write-Host &amp;#34;Domain FSMO Roles:&amp;#34; Write-Host &amp;#34;PDC Emulator: $($domain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Common GPO Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/gpo-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/gpo-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of common uses for GPOs to reference when setting up a Windows Environment.&#xA;User Settings Configuration:&#xA;Setting desktop backgrounds, screen savers, and other personalization options. Configuring browser settings, such as home pages, security settings, and bookmarks. Setting restrictions on control panel access, system settings, and software installation. Computer Configuration:&#xA;Managing security settings like password policies, account lockout policies, and Kerberos policies. Configuring Windows Firewall settings and security options.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Quickstart Guide</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/windows-powershell-quickstart-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/windows-powershell-quickstart-guide/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell Quickstart Guide 1. Introduction PowerShell is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s task automation framework, combining command-line speed, the flexibility of scripting, and the power of a GUI-based admin tool. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re automating tasks, extracting and processing data, or managing systems, PowerShell is a versatile tool to know.&#xA;2. Launching PowerShell You can find PowerShell by searching for it in the Windows start menu. For administrative tasks, it&amp;rsquo;s advisable to run PowerShell as an administrator (right-click the application and select &amp;ldquo;Run as administrator&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Remoting: A Practical Guide for Remote Administration</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/advanced-powershell-remoting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/advanced-powershell-remoting/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell Remoting is a powerful feature for administering remote computers, allowing system administrators to run commands and manage systems from a distance. This guide presents practical exercises to help you leverage PowerShell Remoting for effective network management.&#xA;Exercise 1: Gathering Network Adapter Information Remotely Task: Retrieve Network Adapters from Multiple Computers Initiate from SLC-PC1 VM:&#xA;Begin by logging into the SLC-PC1 virtual machine. Discovering the Command:&#xA;Use the help *adapter* command on SLC-PC1 to find a relevant command for listing network adapters, identifying Get-NetAdapter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Scripting: A Concise Guide</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/powershell-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/powershell-scripting/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell, a combination of a command-line shell and scripting language, offers powerful tools to automate tasks across Windows, Linux, and macOS platforms. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive deep into the realm of PowerShell scripting, exploring advanced topics and techniques with extensive code samples.&#xA;1. Introduction to PowerShell Scripting Originally designed for Windows, PowerShell has extended its reach to other OS platforms, making it a must-know for IT professionals.&#xA;Setting Up the Environment&#xA;PowerShell is pre-installed on modern Windows versions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roles and Responsibilities of Domain Admins and Enterprise Admins in Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/understanding-roles-of-domain-enterprise-admins-in-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/understanding-roles-of-domain-enterprise-admins-in-ad/</guid>
      <description>In the intricate structure of an organization&amp;rsquo;s Active Directory, which spans across forests, domains, and organizational units, the roles of Domain Admins and Enterprise Admins are pivotal for maintaining both effective management and robust security.&#xA;Domain Admins: Masters of the Domain Authority and Responsibilities:&#xA;Domain Admins wield complete control within their specific domains. They are responsible for managing everything from user accounts and domain controllers to group policies and various domain-level resources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Active Directory Domain Services</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/securing-adds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/securing-adds/</guid>
      <description>Securing Active Directory Domain Services (ADDS) is a critical component of maintaining the integrity and security of an organization&amp;rsquo;s IT infrastructure. This guide provides a comprehensive overview of key security practices and configurations necessary for safeguarding your ADDS environment.&#xA;Implementing Strong Password Policies with PSO Understanding PSOs (Password Settings Objects): PSOs are essential for defining password policies specific to user or group accounts in Active Directory. They enable the enforcement of unique password policies that may differ from the domain&amp;rsquo;s default settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up PowerShell Remoting</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/setting-up-remote-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/setting-up-remote-powershell/</guid>
      <description>1. On the Remote Host Enable PowerShell Remoting: You can enable PowerShell Remoting on the remote host by running the following command in an elevated PowerShell session (Run as Administrator):&#xA;Enable-PSRemoting -Force Allow Incoming Connections: Ensure that the Windows Firewall (or any other firewall software you may be using) allows incoming connections for PowerShell Remoting. If using the Windows Firewall, this command will help:&#xA;Set-NetFirewallRule -Name WINRM-HTTP-In-TCP -RemoteAddress Any 2. On the Client Machine (from where you want to initiate the connection) Trust the Remote Host: If your remote host is not part of a domain or the certificate used by the remote host is not trusted, you need to add the remote host to your list of trusted hosts:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steps to Add &#34;Open PowerShell as Administrator&#34; to Context Menu</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/create-open-powershell-as-admin-context-entry-windows-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/create-open-powershell-as-admin-context-entry-windows-explorer/</guid>
      <description>Update Registry Open Registry Editor:&#xA;Press Win + R to open the Run dialog. Type regedit and press Enter. If prompted by User Account Control (UAC), click Yes to continue. Navigate to the Context Menu Key:&#xA;In the Registry Editor, navigate to the following key:&#xA;HKEY_CLASSES_ROOT\Directory\Background\shell You can copy and paste this path into the Registry Editor&amp;rsquo;s address bar.&#xA;Create a New Key for the PowerShell Prompt:&#xA;Right-click on shell, select New &amp;gt; Key, and name it Open PowerShell here as Administrator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Configuring Sites and Subnets in High-Bandwidth Networks</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/the-need-for-sites-and-subnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/the-need-for-sites-and-subnets/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of modern network infrastructures, where high-bandwidth connections like 10 Gbps are common, it might seem that the configuration of traditional Active Directory (AD) sites and subnets is less relevant. However, this perception overlooks the myriad of benefits that a well-configured AD environment can bring, even in high-bandwidth scenarios. Here are several key reasons why configuring AD sites remains a crucial practice:&#xA;Enhanced Authentication and Resource Access: By defining AD sites, you ensure that client authentication occurs at the nearest domain controller.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding AWS CloudFormation Template Syntax</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-cloudformation-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/aws-cloudformation-syntax/</guid>
      <description>Introduction AWS CloudFormation is a powerful service for provisioning and managing AWS infrastructure as code (IAC). To effectively use CloudFormation, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand the syntax of CloudFormation templates, as they serve as the blueprints for your infrastructure. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the essential elements and syntax of CloudFormation templates.&#xA;Format Version&#xA;The AWSTemplateFormatVersion field at the beginning of the template specifies the CloudFormation template version you are using. Example:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Static vs. Instance Methods and Members in PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/accessing-static-methods-and-members-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/accessing-static-methods-and-members-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell&amp;rsquo;s integration with the .NET framework allows for leveraging a variety of functionalities via static and instance members of classes. Grasping the differences between these two types of members is key to proficient scripting and effective system administration.&#xA;Static Methods and Members What Are They? Static methods and members are associated with the class itself rather than any specific object created from the class. They can be accessed directly using the class name, eliminating the need to create an instance of the class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the `param` Keyword in PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/understanding-param/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/understanding-param/</guid>
      <description>In PowerShell, the param keyword is used to define parameters that a script or function can accept. Parameters allow you to pass values into scripts and functions, making them more flexible and reusable. By providing different arguments, users can tailor the behavior of a script or function without modifying its actual code.&#xA;Features of the param Block:&#xA;Positional Parameters: By default, parameters are positional, and values are assigned based on the order they appear in the param block.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Virtual Networking Under the Hood</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-virtual-networking-behind-the-scenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-virtual-networking-behind-the-scenes/</guid>
      <description>VMware Workstation performs a significant amount of low-level networking operations to manage virtual networks for virtual machines (VMs). To achieve this, it installs special drivers and creates virtual network devices that integrate with the host system&amp;rsquo;s networking stack. Here&amp;rsquo;s how VMware modifies your system to enable its networking capabilities:&#xA;Virtual Network Adapters: VMware installs virtual network adapters for different types of networks (like VMnet1 for Host-Only and VMnet8 for NAT by default).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Workstation Pro Networking FAQ</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-virtual-networking-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/vmware-virtual-networking-faq/</guid>
      <description>Contents What does &amp;ldquo;Connect a Host Virtual Adapter to This Network&amp;rdquo; Mean? What IP Address Will the Host Virtual Adapter Receive? Why Does the Host Adapter Get an IP Outside the DHCP Range? Does a NAT Network Require a Host Virtual Adapter to Function? How Does VMware Handle NAT Without a Host Network Adapter? Does VMware Install Special Networking Drivers or Change the Network Stack? What does &amp;ldquo;Connect a Host Virtual Adapter to This Network&amp;rdquo; Mean?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are DNS settings configured per interface?</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/why-different-dns-per-network-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/why-different-dns-per-network-interface/</guid>
      <description>It is kind of complicated&amp;hellip;&#xA;In today&amp;rsquo;s interconnected world, efficient network management and configuration are crucial for maintaining robust and secure IT systems. One aspect of network configuration that often raises questions is the rationale behind setting up individual DNS (Domain Name System) configurations for each network interface. This practice, though seemingly complex, caters to the nuanced needs of diverse network environments – from simple home setups to intricate corporate networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WIM and CIM Lab Exercises</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/cim-lab-exercises/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/cim-lab-exercises/</guid>
      <description>Lab Exercise 1: System Overview Objective: Get an overview of your computer system&amp;rsquo;s properties.&#xA;Task: Retrieve information about the operating system, including its version, last boot up time, and the number of users currently logged on.&#xA;Command Hint: Get-CimInstance -ClassName CIM_OperatingSystem Task: Fetch the computer&amp;rsquo;s name, manufacturer, model, and the total physical memory.&#xA;Command Hint: Get-CimInstance -ClassName Win32_ComputerSystem Lab Exercise 2: Disk Analysis Objective: Analyze the disk space usage and health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WIM, CIM Guide</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/wim-cim-quick-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/wim-cim-quick-guide/</guid>
      <description>1. Retrieve Basic Operating System Information This command fetches basic details about the operating system.&#xA;Get-CimInstance -ClassName CIM_OperatingSystem 2. List All Installed Services Retrieve a list of all services installed on the machine.&#xA;Get-CimInstance -ClassName Win32_Service 3. Get System BIOS Information Displays details about the system&amp;rsquo;s BIOS.&#xA;Get-CimInstance -ClassName Win32_BIOS 4. List All Running Processes Shows all currently running processes on the machine.&#xA;Get-CimInstance -ClassName Win32_Process 5. Check Disk Space Get details about logical disks, including free and used space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Windows Server Core Domain Controller</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/setting-up-server-core-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/setting-up-server-core-dc/</guid>
      <description># Install vmware tools if not installed setup64.exe /s /v&amp;#34;/qn REBOOT=R&amp;#34; # Change the hostname and reboot Rename-Computer -NewName &amp;#39;NewComputerName&amp;#39; Restart-Computer # Remove the old ip address Remove-NetIPAddress -InterfaceAlias &amp;#39;Ethernet0&amp;#39; # Also you might have to remove the default gateway Remove-NetRoute -InterfaceAlias &amp;#39;Ethernet0&amp;#39; -NextHop 10.0.0.2 # Now you can add the new IP Address New-NetIPAddress ` -InterfaceAlias &amp;#39;Ethernet0&amp;#39; ` -IPAddress &amp;#39;10.0.77.104&amp;#39; ` -PrefixLength 24 ` -DefaultGateway &amp;#39;10.0.77.1&amp;#39; # You will also need to set the DNS address Set-DnsClientServerAddress ` -InterfaceAlias &amp;#39;Ethernet0&amp;#39; ` -ServerAddresses &amp;#39;10.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring a DHCP Scope With Windows PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configureing-dhcp-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configureing-dhcp-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description># Define scope parameters $scopeName = &amp;#34;ExampleScope&amp;#34; $startRange = &amp;#34;192.168.1.10&amp;#34; # Starting IP address of the scope $endRange = &amp;#34;192.168.1.100&amp;#34; # Ending IP address of the scope $subnetMask = &amp;#34;255.255.255.0&amp;#34; $gateway = &amp;#34;192.168.1.1&amp;#34; $dnsServers = &amp;#34;192.168.1.2&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;192.168.1.3&amp;#34; # Authorize the DHCP server in Active Directory Add-DhcpServerInDC -DnsName &amp;#34;DhcpServerName&amp;#34; # Add a new DHCP scope Add-DhcpServerv4Scope -Name $scopeName -StartRange $startRange -EndRange $endRange -SubnetMask $subnetMask # Optionally, set additional scope options like default gateway (Router) and DNS servers Set-DhcpServerv4OptionValue -ScopeId $startRange -Router $gateway Set-DhcpServerv4OptionValue -ScopeId $startRange -DnsServer $dnsServers # Note: # - Replace the IP addresses and subnet mask with values appropriate for your network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Windows Server With PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-windows-server-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/configuring-windows-server-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Rename-Computer -NewName &amp;#39;NewComputerName&amp;#39; Restart-Computer # It might be necessary to manually remove dhcp added ip configurations Remove-NetIPAddress -InterfaceAlias &amp;#39;Ethernet0&amp;#39; # Also you might have to remove the default gateway Remove-NetRoute -InterfaceAlias &amp;#39;Ethernet0&amp;#39; -NextHop 10.0.0.2 # Now you can add the new IP Address New-NetIPAddress ` -InterfaceAlias &amp;#39;Ethernet0&amp;#39; ` -IPAddress &amp;#39;10.0.77.101&amp;#39; ` -PrefixLength 24 ` -DefaultGateway &amp;#39;10.0.77.1&amp;#39; # You will also need to set the DNS address Set-DnsClientServerAddress ` -InterfaceAlias &amp;#39;Ethernet0&amp;#39; ` -ServerAddresses &amp;#39;10.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple VMware Windows Infrastructure Lab</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/simple-vmware-windows-infrastructure-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/simple-vmware-windows-infrastructure-lab/</guid>
      <description>Objective This guide provides step-by-step instructions to set up a virtual environment using PowerShell. It includes configuring one Virtual Machine as a Domain Controller (DC), another as an Application Server (APP server), and a Windows 10 Client.&#xA;1. Configure Server2022 as DC To set up the Domain Controller, execute the following commands in PowerShell:&#xA;# Configuring IP address for &amp;#39;Ethernet&amp;#39; interface New-NetIPAddress -IPAddress 10.0.0.2 -InterfaceAlias &amp;#34;Ethernet0&amp;#34; -PrefixLength 24 -DefaultGateway 10.0.0.1 # Set DNS client server address post AD DS installation Set-DnsClientServerAddress -InterfaceAlias &amp;#34;Ethernet0&amp;#34; -ServerAddresses 127.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerShell to Collect Computer Asset Information</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/using-powershell-to-collect-computer-asset-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/using-powershell-to-collect-computer-asset-info/</guid>
      <description># Get computer system and BIOS information $ComputerSystem = Get-CimInstance -ClassName CIM_ComputerSystem $Bios = Get-CimInstance -ClassName CIM_BIOSElement # Check if the information was retrieved successfully if ($ComputerSystem -and $Bios) { # Build the results hashtable $Results = @{ &amp;#39;Computer Name&amp;#39; = $ComputerSystem.Name &amp;#39;Model&amp;#39; = $ComputerSystem.Model &amp;#39;Serial Number&amp;#39; = $Bios.SerialNumber } # Convert the hashtable to a custom PowerShell object $Report = [PSCustomObject]$Results # Clear the host (console) and display the report Clear-Host $Report | Format-Table -AutoSize } else { Write-Error &amp;#34;Failed to retrieve system or BIOS information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YAML Basics</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/yaml-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/yaml-basics/</guid>
      <description>1. Structure:&#xA;YAML uses indentation (spaces, not tabs) to represent the structure, similar to Python. The number of spaces in the indentation is not fixed, but all elements of the list or map must be aligned. 2. Scalars (Strings, Numbers, Booleans):&#xA;Strings can be unquoted or enclosed in single (&#39;) or double quotes (&amp;quot;). Numbers are written as in most programming languages. Booleans are represented with true and false. 3. Lists (Arrays):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory Essentials: Groups, Powershell, and Delegation</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/active-directory-essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/active-directory-essentials/</guid>
      <description>Simplifying Active Directory Group Scopes Understanding Group Types Domain Local Groups: Restricted to a single domain. They manage access within their domain, but not in other domains.&#xA;Global Groups: Span across all domains in a forest. Useful for organizing users within a domain and granting them resource access across the forest.&#xA;Universal Groups: Operate across the entire Active Directory forest. Ideal for large-scale environments needing access across multiple domains.&#xA;Security vs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory Forests, Trees, and Sites, Understanding the Differences</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/ad-forests-trees-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/ad-forests-trees-sites/</guid>
      <description>When navigating the complexities of Microsoft Active Directory (AD), it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand the fundamental building blocks of its architecture: forests, trees, and sites. These terms are often used interchangeably, but they refer to distinct elements within an AD environment.&#xA;Active Directory Forest An Active Directory Forest is the topmost level of the AD structure. Think of a forest as a security boundary within which users, computers, groups, and other objects are managed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIND Troubleshooting Guide (Ubuntu Server)</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/bind-troubleshooting-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/bind-troubleshooting-guide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction BIND (Berkeley Internet Name Domain) is a widely used DNS server software. This guide focuses on troubleshooting BIND on Ubuntu Server 20.04. It assumes that BIND is already installed and configured, and you are experiencing issues.&#xA;Troubleshooting Steps 1. Check BIND Status To get an overview of the BIND service status:&#xA;sudo systemctl status bind9 This command helps identify if BIND is active or if there are any service-related errors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VMware Virtual Network Types and IP Addressing</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/about-vmware-workstation-virtual-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/2023/about-vmware-workstation-virtual-networks/</guid>
      <description>When working with VMware Workstation Pro, setting up your network correctly is crucial for ensuring that your virtual machines (VMs) communicate properly with the host machine and among themselves. VMware provides various types of virtual networks, each serving different needs. This article will cover the three main types: Bridged, NAT, and Host-Only networking.&#xA;Bridged Networking Overview Bridged networking connects a VM directly to the host machine&amp;rsquo;s network, using the host&amp;rsquo;s physical network adapter.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
