<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on gavinmassey.net</title>
    <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on gavinmassey.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gavinmassey.net/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory Forest, Tree, and Site, Understanding the Differences</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/ad-forests-trees-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/ad-forests-trees-sites/</guid>
      <description>When navigating the complexities of Microsoft Active Directory (AD), it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand the fundamental building blocks of its architecture: forests, trees, and sites. These terms are often used interchangeably, but they refer to distinct elements within an AD environment.&#xA;Active Directory Forest An Active Directory Forest is the topmost level of the AD structure. Think of a forest as a security boundary within which users, computers, groups, and other objects are managed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding VMware Virtual Network Types and IP Addressing</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/about-vmware-workstation-virtual-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/about-vmware-workstation-virtual-networks/</guid>
      <description>When working with VMware Workstation Pro, setting up your network correctly is crucial for ensuring that your virtual machines (VMs) communicate properly with the host machine and among themselves. VMware provides various types of virtual networks, each serving different needs. This article will cover the three main types: Bridged, NAT, and Host-Only networking.&#xA;Bridged Networking Overview Bridged networking connects a VM directly to the host machine&amp;rsquo;s network, using the host&amp;rsquo;s physical network adapter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Trusts in Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/ad-infrastructure-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinmassey.net/articles/ad-infrastructure-management/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of network security and management, Trusts within Active Directory (AD) are pivotal. They are the backbone of domain interactions, enabling users in one domain to access resources in another. This guide delves into the intricacies of these trusts, outlining their types, implementations, and best practices for secure and efficient network management.&#xA;Types of Trusts in Active Directory Active Directory trusts can be broadly categorized into several types, each serving a unique purpose in the network infrastructure:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
